Welcome back.
I hope you completed that assignment.
It's really going to help you in the vein of the course and help you to pass your exam.
Now let's talk about three new terms the you need to know these terms and their characteristics and
talking about work performance data work performance information and work performance reports.
We'll see these three terms in all of the knowledge areas are going to be serving as inputs are going
to be serving as outputs.
So work performance data work performance information and reports.
So let's really get a good grasp on these terms.
So we don't have to talk about them in much detail in the remainder of the course.
First off here we have work performance data work performance data as we're talking about the raw data
the facts about the project work.
So as work is done you're able to collect this data.
It's not very usable.
It's just data raw data just pure data about what's going on in the project.
So for example how percent complete is one activity what's the number of activities that have not yet
started.
What's the number of activities that are in progress right now.
What was the planned start date of an activity in the finished date versus the actual start in actual
finish.
So there is all this type of information just raw data just all that stuff that you collect as a project
manager through your status meetings and through your work authorization system and communicating with
your project team.
Data can include like the cost of activities the number of change request number of defects and durations
planned and actual durations.
So data is just raw data.
So the first thing that you have to have in order to create information in reports so data comes first.
Now let's look at work performance information work performance information is where we have the analyzed
work performance data where we've taken that data and we study that we've analyzed that and then from
that we have an ability to make decisions based on that data.
So data becomes information it's informative it's been analyzed and studied and we can use it.
So now we can set that data to actionable results.
So our status is where we are now based on that data based on that information.
I can act on it.
So data to information and now I have actionable results.
So in other words I need the data I need to understand the data so it becomes information and then I
can act on it.
Then we have work performance reports a work performance report is how you package up information so
it becomes communicated.
So work performance information is communicate obal formatting.
So a status report a memo maybe you use a dashboard.
You do project updates every week.
So it's a way of taking data that becomes information and then being able to communicate it clearly.
Most often we're talking status reports here but it could be an exception report.
It could be a variance report could be a risk report it's anything that's packaged up based on information
and data.
Now how you remember these.
It's alphabetical data comes first.
So raw data information is second because you need information to act upon it.
And then once you have that information you want to communicate it so you have to put it in a report.
It's alphabetical data information reports.
OK great.
That's the end of this lecture.
Now you've got three new terms that you've mastered.
Data Information reports.
Keep going.